# Robert Hernandez

# IT PROJECT MANAGER | eCOMMERCE | DATA ANALYTICS

robert@dataloveyou.cloud

(+58) 424-260.81.37

linkedin.com/in/roberthernandezp

## **Profile**

IT Project Manager with over 8 years of experience managing development teams focused on eCommerce and data analytics for Retail companies. I have proven skills in leading multidisciplinary teams, problem solving, and managing eCommerce platforms and marketplaces.

# **Experience**

Freelancer <check my Portfolio>

Project Manager, eCommerce Specialist, Front-end Developer. may 2016 – Present.

I have supported the design, development and implementation of digital projects for different brands, including:

- Pia Luketti, Sportswear retail, I developed eCommerce and digital marketing strategies.
- En Corto Venezuela, sportswear brand, I developed and implemented the eCommerce platform.
- *Grupo Aika*, home accessories retail, I developed the eCommerce platform.

# **Atenas Grupo Consultor** (Market research)

Project Development Manager aug 2022 – feb 2023

- I led the planning and management of IT projects, including migration to the cloud, which resulted in a 15% savings in IT spending (OPEX).
- I supervised a multidisciplinary team in software development, UX/UI design and data analytics, implementing emerging technologies (Cloud) under agile methodologies (Scrum). 10 people.
- I have extensive knowledge of the variables that drive the Retail industry: market share, penetration, sales volume/units/value, groupings by: SKU, categories, geographic areas and socio-economic profiles.

# Tiendas Beco (Retail stores)

Head of Digital Channels mar 2021 – may 2022

- I managed to optimize internal processes and inventory management under Marketplace and Dropshipping models, improving logistics and shipments nationwide, reducing the maximum delivery time for orders to 24 hours.
- I developed commercial strategies to maximize traffic and increase sales by 30% annually.
- I supervised the improvements to the eCommerce platform, including UX/UI design.
- I have extensive knowledge of the factors that determine the success of an eCommerce: traffic, conversion rate, average ticket, purchase frequency, LTV, product assortment, inventories, etc.

# Tiendas IVOO (Retail stores chain)

eCommerce Project Manager jul 2020 – feb 2021

- Responsible for the entire eCommerce structure: back-office, sales, logistics, warehouse and transportation.
- Implemented DCs, distribution centers and fulfillment nationwide.
- Competitor analysis: delivery, rates, pick-ups, promotions and other commercial strategies.
- Designed the integrations between SAP and Back-end (WooCommerce)
- Performed the requirements analysis for the implementation of the Magento Platform.

### **Education**

# North China University of Technology in Beijing. (NCUT)

Global MBA Jul-2014

# Santa Maria University

Bachelor in Business Administration Jan-2009

## **IUTIRLA**

Higher Technician in Computer Science (Esp.: Software Development) Jul-1995

#### **Skills**

- Communication
- Adaptability
- Active listening
- Empathy
- Time management
- Innovation
- Project management
- Agile Scrum
- Software development
- Data analysis and ETL
- E-commerce
- WooCommerce Shopify
- HTML CSS JavaScript
- React.js Next.js
- Node.js Express.js
- Python Jupiter
- SQL Server MySQL
- Machine Learning
- Jira Trello
- $\bullet \ Slack-Notion$
- Git GitHub
- Visual Studio Code
- AWS Cloudflare
- Docker y Kubernetes

### Certificaciones

- Diploma in Retail Management, CIAP-UCAB, 2022
- Diploma in Fashion Business and Brand Management, CIAP-UCAB, 2021
- Diploma in Marketing Digital, Internet Institute, 2018

## **Idiomas**

• Español (Nativo)

• 中文(一点) Chinese

• English (B2)

# **Featured Projects**

- En Corto Venezuela: I implemented WooCommerce and logically organized inventories.
- AutoApp: I conceptualized/designed an App for the automotive industry. UX Wireframes with Figma.
- *ProcessSimulator*: I developed a process queue manager and load balancer software. *JavaScript*.
- Retailcore: I designed processes and data structures for retail market statistics. Python, MySQL
- Préstame Mercantil: I designed and developed this product for Banco Mercantil Credit Cards.
- Behavior Score: Developed and implemented Decision Tree algorithms in Credit Cards.